

# CONTACT

P: 412-526-3809 E: nicholas23smith@gmail.com

# **DEV SKILLS**

- JAVASCRIPT
- HTML
- css
- REACT
- PYTHON
- SQL
- NOSQL
- NODE JS
- JOUERY
- DJANGO

## CERTIFICATIONS

# GENERAL ASSEMBLY | SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE

- 12 week, full-time (60+ hrs/wk) immersive with study in software engineering and web development concepts, practical use-case, and industry best practices.
- Programming Languages: HTML, CSS3, Javascript, Python
- Libraries & Frameworks: Bootstrap, JQuery, Bulma Io, Material, Node, Express, React, Mongoose, Django
- Databases: Postgres, SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB
- Skills: Git, Github, Slack, Responsive Design, Wireframes, Figma, Object-Oriented Programming, AJAX, REST

# GENERAL ASSEMBLY | FRONT END WEB DEVELOPMENT

 Gain hands-on experience with industrystandard tools — HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6) — to build rich, interactive websites

### **EVOLVE SECURITY ACADEMY**

 This module introduces core principles that are essential to forming a security mindset, which include the CIA Triad (Confidentiality / Integrity / Availability), Defense-in-Depth, Authentication, and Authorization.

# SKILLS

- PROBLEM-SOLVING
- LOGICAL THINKING
- SOFTWARE TESTING & DEBUGGING
- TIME & TASK MANAGEMENT
- SELF TEACHABILITY
- TEAM ORIENTED

# NICK SMITH

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

# **ABOUT**

I started immersing myself in technology when I worked in the cybersecurity industry for 2 years gaining insightful knowledge that gave me a firm understanding of best practices in securing one's code and infrastructure. I'm resilient and disciplined in staying focused on completing my goals until the desired outcome is met, and I love going above and beyond, reaching for the stars to outperform expectations, and putting smiles on faces.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

RE:DESIGN - Visual Comunnications, Inc. | Mar 2022 - Present

- Built front-end functionality with HTML5, CSS and Javascript.
- Developed and implemented best practices to achieve the design and aesthetic of the page, requested by the client.
- Devised custom software solutions for functionality of the navigation and website.
- Designed innovative solutions and documented resolutions for inclusion in the knowledge base for support team use.

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER FELLOW

General Assembly Student | Dec 2021 - Mar 2022

- Successfully completed 500+ hours of expert-led instruction in Javascript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, SQL, and hands-on learning of Software Engineering fundamentals and the industries most in-demand technologies. Developed projects, including:
- Pokemon: Built with Javascript, JQuery, CSS, HTML An in-browser Javascript version of the classic Pokemon game. Github: https://github.com/smithereens23nas/Pokemon
- Deployed: https://smithereens23nas.github.io/Pokemon/
- Closed Ocean (NFTs) Built with Javascript, MongoDB, Express, Node.js A MEN-stack project with CRUD functionality for NFTs - Replicating OpenSea Marketplace.
- Github: https://git.generalassemb.ly/smithereens23nas/closedOcean
- Deployed: https://closed-ocean.herokuapp.com/home
- Zauben Built with Postgres, Express, React, Node.js A PERN-stack project building out a client-facing dashboard for the Chicago-based company Zauben, displaying real-time performance metrics for their client's vertical plant wall(s).
- Github (back-end) : https://github.com/smithereens23nas/Zauben-Dashboard-Backend
- Github (front-end): https://github.com/smithereens23nas/Zauben-Dashboard-FrontEnd

#### STRATEGIC PARNERSHIPS

Evolve Security | Apr 2019 - Mar 2020

- Building our sales pipeline with potential clients interested in improving their security posture. Involved in the full sales cycle from prospecting to quote generation to negotiating contracts, and managing client expectations.
- Implementing lead generation best practices and creatively innovating strategies through email templates, A/B sales messaging/testing methodologies, list segmentation, and cold colling.
- Ability to work with the delivery team to craft new solutions to client problems.

#### BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT REPRESENTATIVE

Trustwave | May 2018 - Apr 2019

- Proactively seeking new business opportunities in the enterprise west market
- Set up in-person meetings or calls between Fortune 500 clients and Account Executives/Security Engineers

#### **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR OF ARTS, MAJOR IN MARKETING

Indiana University of Pennsylvania | 2013 - 2017 GPA 3.45